https://help.heinonline.org/kb/what-is-heinonlines-privacy-policy/

Search For
Home
HeinOnline Database Functions, Structure & Technical Information
What is HeinOnline’s Privacy Policy?
What is HeinOnline’s Privacy Policy?
Privacy Notice
Updated:  2019-04-23
This privacy statement describes how William S. Hein & Co., Inc. collects and uses the personal information you provide on the following websites:  https://heinonline.org; https://shop.heinonline.org; https://home.heinonline.org; https://help.heinonline.org;  http://heingreenslips.com; ftp://ftp.wshein.com; and https://www.wshein.com.
Information Collection
To enable access to HeinOnline, calculate overall account usage statistics, and for technical support purposes, we may collect information concerning your internet protocol address, domain name, username and password, or other authentication methods, such as Shibboleth. We also may collect certain non-personally identifiable information, such as the type of browser you are using (e.g., Firefox, Internet Explorer) and the type of operating system you are using (e.g., Windows or Mac)
Server logs are kept for 3 years, specifically for the purpose of providing historical usage statistics.
To facilitate short-term subscriptions from heinonline.org, we may collect your name, username and password, postal address, email address, phone number, and transactional information. We collect but do not store your credit card details through a third party service provider.
In connection with your creation of a MyHein account, we collect your name, email address, username and password, as well as other information you may choose to provide.
If you choose to subscribe to our mailing list, we require your email address, name, organization, job title, and country, as well as other information you may choose to provide.
Cookies
Using HeinOnline requires cookies for authentication purposes.  Session cookies are stored in temporary memory and are not retained after the browser is closed.  Session cookies do not collect information from the user’s computer.
Information Sharing
We are the sole owners of the information collected on our websites.  William S. Hein & Co., Inc. does not sell, give, or trade the personal information we collect to any 3rd parties for data-mining or marketing purposes.
Use of Data
William S. Hein & Co., Inc. uses the collected data for various purposes:
To provide and maintain the Service
To notify you about changes to our Service
To provide customer care and support
To provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the Service
To monitor the usage of the Service
To detect, prevent and address technical issues
The lawful basis for this processing is for the administration of our business and the provision of our services, which is necessary for the legitimate interests of our business.  Processing is also necessary in order for William S. Hein & Co., Inc. to fulfill its contractual obligations (license agreement) to our customers.
Transfer of Data
Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.  If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there.  Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.  William S. Hein & Co., Inc. will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.
Disclosure of Data
Legal Requirements
William S. Hein & Co., Inc. may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:
To comply with a legal obligation
To protect and defend the rights or property of William S. Hein & Co., Inc.
To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
To protect against legal liability
Security
We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.  While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (e.g. billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.
Links to Other Sites
Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.
We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.
Children’s Privacy
Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”).
We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.
Data Retention
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at holsupport@wshein.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.  MyHein account data is stored indefinitely, but users may delete their own MyHein accounts and all associated data at any time (MyHein menu, “delete your MyHein account”)
Your Rights as a Data Subject
You have rights as a data subject. These rights are:
The right to be informed– this means we must inform you how we are going to use your personal data. We do this through this privacy policy and by informing you how your data will be used each time we collect it.
The right of access– you have the right to access your personal data that we hold. This is called a subject access request. We must respond to your request within one month. To request access to your data, please email holsupport@wshein.com. Please include the personal data you are seeking.
The right to rectification– if you think the data we hold on you is incorrect, you may let us know and we will correct it. You can do this by emailing holsupport@wshein.com.
The right to erasure – you have the right to request that we delete your data.  To request this, please email holsupport@wshein.com
The right to restrict processing– you can change your communication preferences (therefore restricting how we communicate with you) by emailing holsupport@wshein.com
The right to data portability– you can obtain and reuse your personal data for your own purposes across different services. To request this, please email holsupport@wshein.com
The right to object– you have the right to object to a) Direct marketing from William S. Hein & Co., Inc. You can opt out of direct marketing any time by emailing holsupport@wshein.com. There will also be instructions on how to unsubscribe included in any direct marketing message that we send to you.  b) Any processing where our lawful basis is legitimate interest (see “use of data” section above). If you would like to formally object to any of our legitimate interest processing, please email holsupport@wshein.com.
Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling– this is not something we do at William S. Hein & Co., Inc. If that ever changes, this policy will be updated accordingly.
Notification of Privacy Policy Changes
We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
Contact Us
If you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, you should contact us immediately.  The data controller responsible for your personal information for the purposes of the applicable European Union data protection law is:
William S. Hein & Co., Inc.
ATTN: Data Protection Officer
2350 North Forest Rd.
Was this article helpful?
Yes
No
Related Articles
How to Navigate within Titles, Volumes, Sections, and Pages
How to Navigate within Titles, Volumes, Sections, and Pages (Video)
How to Use Fuzzy Searching
Does Chrome Support Referring URLs?
What is the EZproxy stanza for HeinOnline?
CASA Enabled in HeinOnline
How to Use Boosting in a Search Query
Are the URLs in HeinOnline persistent?
Does HeinOnline support Open URL resolvers such as SFX?
Is Endnote compatible with HeinOnline?
PDF shows up as a placeholder icon in browser. How can I fix this?
When I download a PDF article it results in a blank page and/or blank screen. How can I fix this?
How to Construct a URL to a Specific Citation Using an Open URL Resolver
Downloading, Printing, and Sharing Documents
Top Tips Every Researcher Should Know
HeinOnline Comprehensive User’s Guide
What information is contained in each KBART data field?
What is KBART?
Can I Use a Citation To Retrieve a Document?
Using Syntax and Field Searching in the Main Full Text Search Bar
When I download a PDF from HeinOnline, there is a red X where the PDF should be. What can I do?
I am unable to save the PDF I downloaded. My operating system is Windows Vista. What should I do?
How Do I Print or Download a Document?
What are the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) and is HeinOnline compliant?
What are the definitions of the content section types in HeinOnline search results?
Database Descriptions for Libguides
Recommended Configurations
HeinOnline User Rules
Approved Discovery Services & How They Work with HeinOnline
How Do I Download a Document That Exceeds 200 Pages?
May I use the HeinOnline logo?
What is Section 508?
Will I need to adjust authentications or proxy settings to access case law powered by Fastcase?
What are the supported authentication methods for HeinOnline access?
How To Get a Permanent Link To a Title?
How Do I Construct a Search Using Boolean Operators?
What is an external section type?
How do I Build a Wildcard Search?
How Do I Use Proximity Searching to find a Phrase Within 10 words of Another Phrase or Word?
How do I search within results?
How Do I Search by Author?
How I convert the PDF file into a WORD document?
Are the URLs in HeinOnline durable?
Does HeinOnline support federated searches?
Where can I download Adobe Flash?
Are PDFs in HeinOnline searchable?
Where can I download Adobe Reader?
My organization uses OneLog for access to our electronic resources. Are there any known problems with OneLog?
Is Endnote compatible with HeinOnline?
How can I Obtain a List of Titles in a Library?
The HeinOnline Instruction Videos Won’t Play on My System.
PDF Shows up as a Placeholder Icon in Browser.
Downloading PDF article results in a blank page and/or blank screen.
How can I make a PDF smaller in size for e-mail?
When I download a PDF from HeinOnline I get “Error: The PDF is damaged.” What can I do?
What version of Adobe Reader is compatible with HeinOnline?
Which web browsers are supported in HeinOnline?
What are the system requirements for printing in HeinOnline?
What are the system requirements for using HeinOnline?
Frequently Asked Questions – System Requirements
Type and Press “enter” to Search
